William Francis Gray Swann Papers 1903-1962 Mss.B.Sw1
American Philosophical Society
- Series V. Images and Certificates, ca.1920s-1962; 1.0 Linear feet
  - Photographs from APS Photograph Collection.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group portrait, standing outside on steps., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of men standing on steps, building in background, Swann standing front row, center.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group portrait, standing outside., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of men and women standing outside, Swann standing second row center.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, informal group portrait, interior., 1.0 Photograph(s); Informal group portrait, Swann center rear.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group portrait, outside, building in background., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of men, seated and standing; Swann seated in first row.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group portrait, building in background., 1.0 Photograph(s); Large group of men and woman, seated and standing outside, Swann seated in front row, near center.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group portrait, informal, interior., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group of men and women, seated and standing, Swann standing near center.
    - W. F. G. Swann sitting on steps, informal group portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, men and women seated and standing; Swann seated, second row on right.
    - W. F. G. Swann and Richard T. Sollenberger, holding teacups., 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length view of Swann and Sollenberger, wearing name tags and holding teacups.
    - W. F. G. Swann sitting with others at table in banquet hall., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of banquet hall, Swann seated, with others, at table.
    - W. F. G. Swann with unidentified man, examining a topographical glove., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann, sitting with hands on knees, as unidentified man demonstrates a piece of equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group portrait, outside building., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, building in background; Swann third to right, front row.
    - W. F. G. Swann, accepting award, 3/4 view., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length portrait of Swann, shaking hands with unidentified man, standing with others, statue of Benjamin Franklin in background.
    - W. F. G. Swann, at awards ceremony, Dr. Adams receiving Franklin Medal., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann, Dr. Adams, and three unidentified men standing at awards ceremony.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others in tuxedos, group portrait at Franklin Institute., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of men in tuxedos; Swann in back row.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group porait, standing outside., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, Swann second to right, front row.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others, group portrait at Medal Metting of Franklin Institute., 1934 May 16; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of Swann and other recipients of awards at Medal Meeting of the Franklin Institute.
    - W. F. G. Swann standing at microphone, hands in pockets., 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of Swann speaking at microphone.
    - W. F. G. Swann, laughing, with unidentified men, group portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Informal group portrait of Swann and others.
    - W. F. G. Swann, seated at table, unidentified man at microphone., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann, laughing and touching the arm of the man at the microphone, is seated at long table, probably banquet at Franklin Institute.
    - W. F. G. Swann, speaking with unidentified man., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann, back to photographer, bending to speak to unidentified man, others standing nearby.
    - W. F. G. Swann, standing and laughing, seated women looking on., 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length view of Swann, women seated with hats.
    - W. F. G. Swann, standing outside with two women., 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length portrait of Swann and others standing outside building.
    - W. F. G. Swann, standing with other men, placing items in corner stone., ca. 1950; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Swann, standing with others, at corner stone ceremony.
    - W. F. G. Swann and Niels Bohr, at Franklin Institute., 1933 May 4; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length, group portrait of Swann and Bohr.
    - W. F. G. Swann with E. Newton Harvey and Alfred Lee Loomis at Franklin Institue Medal Meeting., 1934 May 16; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length portrait of Swann and others.
    - W. F. G. Swann with Dr. Szanto and Dimitri Mitropoulos at Philadelphia Musical Academy 76th Commencement., 1946 June 20; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of the three men in academic robes.
    - W. F. G. Swann seated beside unidentified man., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann and unidentified man seated outside.
    - W. F. G. Swann, seated with others., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann, on couch, seated with wife and others.
    - W. F. G. Swann seated with wife and others., 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann, on couch, with three women.
    - W. F. G. Swann and wife, on couch., 1.0 Photograph(s); Mr. and Mrs. Swann, seated.
    - W. F. G. Swann seated outside., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Swann seated outside with others, plants in background.
    - W. F. G. Swann, half length portrait, blackboard with equations in background., 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length, 3/4 view portrait of Swann, equations in background.
    - W. F. G. Swann, formal portrait, wearing beret., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Bust length, formal portrait of Swann, wearing beret.
    - Group portrait outside, Swann standing on right., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, outside, Swann on right.
    - Group portrait, ouside under tree, Swann seated, first row., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, outside, building and automobile in background.
    - Group portrait, outside on steps, Swann seated first row., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, outside on steps, Swann in first row.
    - Group portrait, outside on steps, Swann seated, second row center., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, seated outside on steps.
    - Group portrait, outside, Swann seated second row, right., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, outside.
    - Group portrait, outside, Swann standing, back row., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, outside, windows in background.
    - Group portrait, Swann seated front row center., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, outside, seated on steps.
    - Half length view of unidentified woman, wearing mink shawl and white gloves., 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of woman.
    - Portrait of unidentified man, wearing bow tie., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Portrait of man with bow tie.
    - Portrait of unidentified man., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Portrait of man with bow tie.
    - S. R. Milner [?], formal profile., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Formal, profile, mounted photograph of Milner (?).
    - "All this Judge needs is a Violon-Cello.", n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Full length view of Louis D. Brandeis.
    - View of boardroom., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of room with board table and bookshelves.
    - View of study, painting of W. F. G. Swann on far wall., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of study with desk and other furniture.
    - View of people on horses in Grand Canyon., 1930 August 22; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of people on horseback in Grand Canyon.
    - View of ship crew., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of crew members, standing on ship.
    - View of Swann, standing with others, on ship., 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann, standing with two women and a man, on ship.
    - W. F. G. Swann and others leaning on ship railing., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of Swann and four other people, outside on ship.
    - W. F. G. Swann, standing on steps on ship., 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait of Swann, standing on steps.
    - W. F. G. Swann, standing shipboard., 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait of Swann, hands in pockets.
    - W. F. G. Swann, two women and a man, standing deck of ship., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of Swann and others, standing outside on ship.
    - W. F. G. Swann standing, arms akimbo, with others in Mexico., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, Swann standing in back.
    - View of post office, Canberra, Australia., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Exterior view of post office.
    - Internal view of Austrailian Institute of Anaotomy, Canberra., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); View of skeletons, bones and skulls, in the Australian Institute of Anatomy.
    - Internal view of the House of Parliament, Australia., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Internal view of Australian House of Parliament.
    - "The King's Hall, Parliament, where President's reception was held.", n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Interior view of Australian Parliament.
    - "Onward and Upward. First Annual Dinner, York Place O. B. Association.", 1902 December 6; 1.0 Photograph(s); Promotional collection of photographs; Swann pictured second to right, top row.
    - W. F. G. Swann, with two other men, inspecting equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of Swann and others, examining equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann and unidentified man examining equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann, standing with unidentified man, examining equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann and unidentified man constructing equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann and unidentified man, laughing, working on equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann and unidentified man working with scientific equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Swann and unidentified man examining equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann and unidentified man, examining equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann and unidentified man looking at equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann bending over box, examining equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann, looking at equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann connecting wires on scientific equipment, unidentifed man looking on., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length view of Swann and unidentified man working with equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, examining equipment, full length view., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann, inspecting equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, foot on chair, working on equipment with unidentified man., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann and unidentified man, working on equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, full length view, examining equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann, inspecting equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, full length view, outside, examining equipment with unidentified man., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann and unidentified man, standing outside, with equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, holding scientific equipment, standing with unidentified man., 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of Swann, holding equipment, standing outside.
    - W. F. G. Swann in laboratory, posing with equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann with equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, working with equipment, metal gondola for stratosheric flight in background., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann, working with equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, seated at desk, working with equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of Swann, seated, examining equipment.
    - W. F. G. Swann, looking through microscope., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Swann, looking through microscope.
    - Hendrik Antoon Lorentz, full length portrait., 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Lorentz, standing on steps.
    - Group of unidentified men examining equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of men, seen from above, examining equipment.
    - Two unidentified men examining equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Two men looking at equipment.
    - Two unidentified men, standing beside scientific equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); Two men, standing beside and examining equipment.
    - Unidentified woman, seated, examining scientific equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of woman, inspecting equipment.
    - View of unidentifed man standing beside scientific equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); Laboratory with scientific equipment.
    - Unidentified scientific equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Scientific equipment.
    - View of scientific equipment, three structures., 1.0 Photograph(s); Three structures.
    - View of scientific equipment., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of equipment on table.
    - View of scientific equipment., 1.0 Photograph(s); View of equipment.
    - Group portrait of children in front of Piccard Stratosphere Flight vessel., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait with Swann and Piccard standing in row.
    - Group portrait of children, standing, near Piccard Stratosphere Flight vessel., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait with Swann standing on far left and Piccard sitting on vessel.
    - View of crowd of children gathered around the Piccard Stratosphere Flight vessel., 1.0 Photograph(s); Crowd gathered around vessel, Piccard on top, removing equipment, Swann standing on left.
    - "1500 Hydrogen Flasks for Inflating Balloon" postcard., 1935; 1.0 Item(s); View of hydrogen flasks.
    - Captain Albert Stevens, scientific observer on stratosphere flight, postcard., 1935; 1.0 Item(s); Full length view of Captain Stevens, preparing for flight.
    - "Constructing Gondola" postcard., 1935; 1.0 Item(s); Full length view of two men constructing the gondola for the Explorer II flight.
    - "Constructing Largest Balloon Every Built" postcard., 1935; 1.0 Item(s); View of deflated balloon being spread out and held by circle of people.
    - Governor Tom Berry, Major Keppner and Captina Stevens, in front of medal gondola for stratosphere flight, postcard., 1935; 1.0 Item(s); Berry, Keppner and Stevens, standing in front of gondola.
    - Scale models of the gondola used in the stratosphere flight, postcard., 1935; 1.0 Item(s); Models of apparatus carried during the flight.
    - View of Stratophere Bowl, postcard., 1935; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of site from which stratosphere flight balloon launched, tents visible.
    - "View of Stratosphere Bowl (You are Standing Here Now)" postcard., 1935; 1.0 Item(s); View of natural bowl used to launch the Explorer II stratosphere flight balloon, with indication of where the viewer would be standing under unknown circumstances.
    - Two unidentifed men in flight suits., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of two men in flight suits with scientific equipment.
    - View of scientific equipment for stratosphere flight., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Internal view of gondola used for stratosphere flight.
    - Major Keppner (?), Captain Stevens and unidentified man, standing in front of gondola for stratosphere flight., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of three men standing in front of gondola.
    - Exterior view of apparatus being constructed for stratosphere flight., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of wooden structure being built.
    - View of two unidentified men, one standing in balloon basket., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of men and balloon basket.
    - Full length view, two unidentified men, standing outside, working on equipment for stratospheric flight., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men working with equipment.
    - Two unidentified men, standing outside, working on equipment for stratospheric flight, 3/4 view., 1935 November; 1.0 Item(s); View of two men working with equipment.
    - Two men, seated at table with NBC microphone, gondola for stratosphere flight in background., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men seated, preparing radio communication for stratosphere flight.
    - View of men working on scientific equipment for stratospheric flight., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of equipment, two men standing behind.
    - View of personal of U.S. Army Air Corps Stratosphere Flight., 1935; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of personal, working with scientific equipment.
    - Interior view of gondola for stratosphere flight, with NBC mircrophone., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Interior view of gondola.
    - Internal view of gondola for stratosphere flight., 1935; 1.0 Photograph(s); Internal view of gondola, equipment used for flight visible.
    - View of gondola being wheeled into place for stratosphere flight., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); Gondola, on wheels, being moved for flight preparation.
    - View of balloon rising from stratosphere bowl., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of balloon being inflated.
    - Beginning Ascent from 12,000 feet over Pine Ridge Indian Reservation., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View from balloon during stratosphere flight.
      Photograph taken during National Geographic-Army Air Corps stratosphere flight.
    - View of inflated balloon for stratosphere flight, seen from groundlevel., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of inflated balloon, held by ropes to the ground.
    - View of inflated balloon for stratosphere flight, seen from above., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of inflated balloon, circled by lights.
    - 12,000 feet, lowering electrograph., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of balloon lowering electrograph, to measure rays in the stratosphere.
    - View of scientific balloon at 20,000 feet., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of balloon at 20,000 feet.
    - View of scientific balloon at 24,000 feet., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of balloon in flight.
    - Borglum Memorial., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of memorial, cut into mountain.
    - Devil's Tower., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Devil's Tower.
    - Mount Shasta from the Northwest., 1935 November; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Mount Shasta.
    - View from scientific balloon, "over eroded bad lands.", 1.0 Photograph(s); View from balloon in flight.
    - W. F. G. Swann, playing cello., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Swann, playing cello.
    - W. F. G. Swann, playing cello, unidentified man playing piano., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of Swann playing cello, man seated at piano, nude statue in forefront.
      Handwritten note on reverse: "To professor Swann, the magician of tunes and rays! With admiration, Lilly Rona."
  - Lantern Slides, 281 slides (Box 116 - 120)
- Series VI. Motion picture films, 22.0 Film reel(s)
  Twenty-two 16mm films, transferred to DVD as part of the Save America's Treasures grant in December 2006. See archivist for access to reader copies. Films Nos. 16 and 18 could not be transferred due to damage. All original films are in cold-storage.
  - Film 1: Hunting Cosmic Rays in a B-29. Color. Approx 15 minutes. Produced by National Geographic Foundation. Footage of the cosmic ray experiments conducted in a B-29 by the National Geographic Foundation and the Bartol Research Foundation.
  - Film 2: Piccard Flight. B/W. Stratosphere flight of Jean and Jeannette Piccard, Oct 23, 1934, from Ford Airport, Dearborn, MI, to Cadiz, OH.
  - Film 3: Home Movie. B/W. Approx. 11 minutes. Includes scenes of Swann playing cello, groundbreaking of Bartol Research Foundation on campus of Swarthmore, Swann playing tennis, early images of Benjamin Franklin Parkway.
  - Film 4: Home Movie. B/W. Approx. 5 minutes. Appears to be footage of trips abroad.
  - Film 5: Home Movie. B/W. Footage of an unidentified woman in various locations in Paris.
  - Film 6: Stratosphere Balloon Flight. B/W. Approx 3 minutes. Unidentified Balloon flight. Shows Swann working various apparatus.
  - Film 7: Stratosphere Balloon Flight. B/W. Unidentified Balloon flight. Film then switches to footage of Independence Square
  - Film 8: Home Movie. B/W. Approx. 3 minutes. Unidentified family.
  - Film 9: Home Movie. B/W. Swann and an unidentified man outside the Bartol Research Foundation at Swarthmore.
  - Film 10: Home Movie. B/W. Unidentified persons onboard a ship.
  - Film 11: Home Movie. B/W. Approx. 3 minutes. Includes footage of an observatory.
  - Film 12: Home Movie. B/W. Appears to be footage of trips abroad. Includes images of a cemetery and a funeral procession. Also an unidentified man playing the violin.
  - Film 13: Home Movie. B/W. Visit to Redwood National Forrest.
  - Film 14: Home Movie. B/W. Man playing cello.
  - Film 15: Home Movie. B/W. Includes footage of orchestra concert in an outdoor amphitheater.
  - Film 17: Home Movie. B/W. Footage of laboratory equipment operating. Blurry.
  - Film 19: Home Movie. B/W. Includes footage of Swann feeding a deer.
  - Film 20: Home Movie. B/W. Approx. 4 minutes. Includes footage of street preachers, onboard ship, a cat.
  - Film 21: Home Movie. B/W. Includes footage of a house under construction.
  - Film 22: Home Movie. B/W.